[roars]
[narrator]
Strange beasts
and monsters.
[squeaking]
Vast riches.
Hidden treasures.
Evil haunts.
Uncharted frontiers.
The mysterious unknown.
The people who are captivated
by the magic in those words...
are called...
Hunters.
[theme music playing]
Guess I’ll let go, then.
Whoa, whoa, whoa! Hold on, don’t let go!
I’m awake!
[Majitani groans]
[clock beeps]
Even so,
you have only twenty hours remaining.
I know. But at least now we’re in
a better position with a two-one lead.
Now,
let's keep this ball rolling.
The choice is yours.
So, what’s it gonna be?
TROUBLE x WITH x THE GAMBLE
[narrator] In the five-on-five battle
with the prisoners,
Gon and friends lead two-to-one.
They’re one win away from victory.
Round four is a series of bets
with time as the currency.
What will they bet on next?
Well? Let’s hear it.
What’s the next wager gonna be, huh?
Or did you lose your nerve
when I saw through your little scam?
[Leroute chuckles]
Very well.
LEROUTE 112-YEAR SENTENCE ILLEGAL GAMBLING
AND ENDANGERED SPECIES TRAFFICKING
[Leorio]
Damn, she's really cute.
[laughs bashfully]
What a pervert.
I hear his heartbeat from here.
I don’t like where this is heading.
All right.
What do you say we place bets on
whether I’m a man or a woman?
Huh?
What’s the matter?
That isn’t a problem, is it?
[Leorio]
Uh, no.
She is definitely a woman.
Or maybe she’s a cross-dresser?
No way. She’s gotta be a woman.
Fine, I accept.
But what if I bet you’re a man?
How exactly are you gonna prove
you’re not?
Oh, right.
I promise to let you examine
every square inch of my body.
Now, will that satisfy you?
[Leorio]
Yeah....
Her body?
[laughs excitedly in his head]
He’s already chosen.
He’ll bet she’s a man.
-Yeah.
-[Gon] Huh? Why?
[Leorio]
I've made up my mind.
And I’ll wager ten hours
that you’re actually a man!
[Leroute scoffs]
I knew it.
Dirty, stinkin’ old man…
But... how did you know?
[Leorio]
This way,
even if I’m wrong and she is a woman
still get to check out her body!
Either way,
talk about a win-win situation!
Actually, I hope I’m wrong!
Do you get it now?
Yeah, I do.
Okay, reveal the answer!
That’s too bad. I’m really a woman.
[gulps]
Oh, you are, huh?
Well, want to check for yourself?
Well, don’t mind if I do.
I mean, just to be fair, of course.
[Leorio laughing]
[beeping]
[Leorio]
I regret nothing.
[Gon sighs]
It is physically painful to watch this.
[Tonpa]
He's going to lose.
No question. She can already see
right through his strategy.
He’s betting safe.
It’s obvious.
Hedging his bets to minimize the damage.
He’s the kind of gambler
who tries to avoid losing
instead of trying to win.
That kind of betting
never takes home the prize.
[Leorio chuckling]
Sorry to say it, boys, but Leorio
just doesn’t have what it takes.
[Leroute] I thought so.
His gambling style is
nothing to worry about.
If he keeps playing that way,
he doesn’t have a prayer.
[chuckles]
Well?
Your turn to pick what we bet on next.
So what do you wanna wager?
[Leorio]
This is no time to celebrate.
I've only got ten hours left to bet with.
Leorio has no room for error.
Losing the next bet would tie the score
up at two-to-two.
And then we lose 50 hours,
leaving very little time
to clear the tower.
[Gon] Leorio.
Okay, what to bet on…
I can’t afford to lose
but I can’t think of a sure-fire win.
Hey, I got it!
We’ll bet on whether I’m a really man
or just a woman in disguise
No, that’s never gonna work.
Gotta think of something else.
Keep it to yourself, old man.
Thinking out loud
isn’t how you plan a strategy!
I know.
-[Gon] Leorio!
-Huh?
How ‘bout you bet on whether or not
you’re a teenager?
Give me a break, Gon.
There’s no way I look that old
and you all know it!
I’m clearly a teenager!
He's... a teenager?
Wow, he looks like an old man.
All right! I know what we’re betting on.
Let’s bet on who’ll win
rock paper scissors!
[giggles]
Why not.
Is he serious?
Why did he have to pick
such a difficult wager?
Wait.
What’s so hard about rock paper scissors?
[Leorio scoffs]
Just so happens,
rock paper scissors is my specialty.
In fact, I just played a tournament
in the shopping district
and I won a gourmet vacation.
Let's see.
So for my wager, I’ve got eighty hours
that say I’ll win, okay?
Eh... Did you just say 80?
That’s not a problem, is it?
I'm free to bet however much I want.
Uh...
I guess there's no rule against it.
Perfect. And if you lose,
I can only take ten from you
since that’s all you have left.
So don't worry.
[Leorio]
She doesn't need to bet 80 hours.
Ten's plenty.
I mean, what if she loses?
Is she that confident
in her rock paper scissors skills?
[Leroute] As expected,
he's starting to stress out. [giggles]
I can read him like an open book.
While the rules
of rock paper scissors are simple,
the game itself can be incredibly complex.
From the perspective of probability,
you only stand a one-in-three chance
of losing any given round.
But if your opponent can predict
your reasoning
and control your reactions,
your chance of losing
increases dramatically.
In short, this is a game of wits
and Leorio is pretty lacking
in that department.
I see.
[Leorio]
Okay, I'm ready.
[chuckles]
Hey, what's so funny?
It’s just I can already tell
what you’re going to use.
I’m something of a mind reader, you see.
That is a lie.
You can bluff all you want, but it’ll take
a lot more than that to scare me!
You’ll believe it soon…
[Leroute giggles] Just like I planned.
One blatant lie and he's losing it.
[Leorio]
Can she really read minds?
No, she’s lying. She’s gotta be.
But what if she isn't?
Leorio will use rock.
You ready?
-And... rock, paper, scissors.
-Scissors.
You were right.
Good guess, Kurapika.
Leorio was nervous,
leading him to avoid any actions
that involved opening up.
She's good.
She’s doing everything she can
to make him uncomfortable
and less likely to use paper.
So, she sticks to rock,
ensuring either a win or a draw.
Like I said,
Rock-paper-scissors is
actually a mind game.
Now I see.
Hang on.
We both used rocks,
so that was a draw, wasn't it?
So what if it was?
Ha! I knew it!
You were lying about being able
to read my mind!
If you really were a psychic,
then you would have beaten me! Right?!
[giggles]
[Leorio]
What are you laughing at?
I gave you that tie on purpose.
You’re welcome.
Quit lying!
Have you forgotten already?
We’re trying to stall you here
for as long as possible.
If I really wanted to,
I could force a series of draws
that would last indefinitely.
But why?
I’m sure that wouldn’t be half as fun
as toying with you.
But I’ll end it after this.
Well, what will you use next?
Come on, think hard. [laughs]
Damn it!
[Leroute]
Yes, that's it. .
Worry. Fret.
[Kurapika]
Worrying, fretting.
Whenever someone’s confidence
is shattered,
they begin to crave reassurance.
See? That’s obviously
what’s happening to Leorio.
He'll use the same play,
play or something stronger
to regain his confidence.
I see what she's doing.
She's trying to get Leorio to choose
either rock or paper.
Correct.
Using paper means
she’s certain not to lose.
Then Leorio’s gotta stay one step ahead!
Indeed.
And if he were calmer,
he might actually be able to.
-[Gon] Leorio!
-Now what?
Listen! If you want to win,
you’ve gotta play scissors!
Scissors, what?
[giggles]
Go ahead, try.
[Leorio] But if I do,
she's just going to use rock.
No. She’ll go a step further
and choose paper.
Unless she goes even further
and picks scissors.
Or she might jump ahead
and go straight to rock…
[screams]
What is happening!
Here we go.
Here comes the draw!
[beeping]
[cries out]
I win, yay!
[laughing]
Amazing.
This game’s really hard.
And now the score’s two-two.
Even worse, we have far less time
now that we’ve lost the 50 hours
he gambled with.
[Leorio] Sorry, I thought I was
a rock paper scissors pro.
[Tonpa scoffs]
Pretty pathetic showing.
What did you say?
Yeah,
I guess I can't argue with you there.
Okay. So how much time do they have left?
How did I do?
[chuckles]
Fifty-nine hours, forty-five minutes.
Not bad.
By my calculations, that means
they’ve now got fewer than ten hours
to reach the bottom.
It doesn't matter how much time they have.
[gasping]
[man] It doesn't matter
because my opponent is about to die.
HUNTER GLOSSARY
ROCK-PAPER-SCISSORS
So the final round is upon us.
I guess that means I’m up.
Huh? Wait, Killua?
What does that mean?
Damn, this sucks!
I really needed to win my round.
It’s all my fault!
Gon, your buddy, here, is pissing me off.
Take it easy.
Don’t throw in the towel.
We don’t even know
what the next contest is yet.
But if it’s something
like doing math in your head,
I’m totally surrendering.
Hey, you’re right
If the next opponent’s a weakling,
we might still have a chance!
[Bendot]
That kid's their last member.
I didn’t think he’d draw the short straw.
That poor thing. He’s still so young.
[Lippo] I did everything I could
to avoid using him.
However, the Hunter Exam isn’t the time
or the place
for showing mercy.
If he dies, well, that’s fate.
Removing his handcuffs.
[handcuffs click]
I don’t get it.
What are you guys scared of?
Stop, you idiot.
He doesn’t look all that terrifying to me.
That's all ancient histor--
[gasping]
It's that guy...
You know him?
We should just take the loss.
Killua, you can't fight this guy.
Why not?
[Leorio] Johness, the Dissector...
SERIAL KILLER SERVING A 968-YEAR SENTENCE
The worst mass murderer
in Zaban’s history.
He chose his victims at random.
It was all over the news.
146 people.
Men, women, young, old, all slaughtered.
Each of the victims had
one thing in common.
He murdered every single one of them
with his bare hands.
His grip was infamous.
The raw power in his fingers alone…
It was unreal.
It’s been ages
since I last touched human flesh.
He’s a complete psychopath.
You don’t have to fight him!
There's always next year, right?.
Hey, Killua!
Killua!
What the hell?!
Wasn’t he listening to a word I just said?
Let him go, Leorio.
He might have a plan
we don't know about.
[music playing]
How do you want to do this?
[Johness]
Do this?
You have the wrong idea.
See, you’re about to be
on the wrong side of a one-sided massacre.
I don't care about the Exam
or reducing my sentence.
All I want is to hear you scream.
Really? Fine.
We'll just keep fighting
until one of us dies.
That's right.
A battle to the death.
-Soon... I'll tear your body apart
-[wind rustles]
with just my bare hands, you got it?
[heart beats]
[gasping]
[struggles to breathe]
What happened?
Why am I so cold?
[heart beats]
That's mine...
[grunts]
It belongs to me.
[beating grows weaker]
Give it back. Give it to me.
[beating slows]
[gasping weakly]
[beeping]
So, that's three wins for us.
We move on, right?
That's right. Yeah, you guys win.
By the way,
you must be itching for some action.
You didn't get to fight.
How about it?
Want to take me on?
Thanks but no thanks.
Suit yourself.
Whoa, who is this kid, anyway?
That's right, you guys don't know?
Wait. Know what?
Killua's family. He says
they're a bunch of elite assassins.
[surprised gasp]
Did you say elite assassins?
[Killua] I'm back.
What?
Just... good work out there!
[Lippo]
Please cross the bridge.
[over PA] On the other side,
you'll find a small room.
That's where you'll be spending
the 50 hours you gambled away.
Well, come on.
-[Gon] Mm-hmm.
-All right, sure.
[voice over PA] Gittarackur,
applicant 301, is the second to pass.
Time elapsed, 12 hours and two minutes.
Something told me
you'd already passed the finish line.
[Hanzo]
All right!!
-[over PA] Applicant 294, is the third...
-I'm the first one to finish!
What the...?
-...twelve hours and three minutes.
-Oh!
I don't believe it.
I came in third place.
[rumbling]
[beeping]
Oh, come on, give me a break.
Can't believe we've got to sit around here
for 50 hours.
-Killua.
-Huh?
Can you tell me how
that technique works?
What do you mean "technique".
The one you used
to instantly remove his heart.
Oh, that one.
Well, it wasn't a technique, really.
I just ripped it out.
[Kurapika] That's all?
To be honest... I did manipulate
my body some. Made it a lot easier.
Whoa! Your nails!
Oh, wow.
Mass murderers talk big,
but they're still just amateurs.
I used to be a professional.
But my old man would have done
a lot better.
When he takes a heart,
there's not even a drop of blood.
[laughs nervousy]
That's good to know. Thanks, kid.
[Kurapika]
At least he's on our side.
All right then,
we've got more than two days.
So what do you want to do?
We've got to do something.
First, let's search the room to see
if there's anything to play with.
Okay.
Kids! Not a care in the world, huh?
Time to take a load off.
[narrator] Gon's team of five passed
the trial
with three wins and two losses.
But now must spend their
50-hour penalty here.
Unfortunately,
they're running out of time.
[beeping]
[theme music plays]
[Gon] Next time.
"Final Test of Resolve."
You have to think like a fish!
-[Killua] Seriously?
-[Gon] Yep!